homehardware.ca 2018-08-17

# Privacy Policy Home Hardware - Home Hardware

At Home Hardware Stores Limited we understand the importance of your personal privacy. We have instituted policies and procedures to ensure that any personal information you provide to us, as a result of our relationship with you, will be treated with the utmost care and respect. We will treat your personal information just as carefully as we would treat our own. Please take a moment to review our privacy commitment to you.

## 1\. WHY WE COLLECT, USE AND RETAIN YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Home Hardware Stores Limited collects personal information about individuals in order to better manage its relationship with them. When you participate in our national marketing programs or customer surveys we require certain personal information to fulfil our commitment to you.

We may also track your use of Home Hardware Stores Limited website using common tools including cookies, google tag manager and floodlights. This helps us analyze the effectiveness of our advertising, and help us determine the correct assortments and services desired by our customers to so we can serve your better. 

## 2\. COLLECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Home Hardware Stores Limited will only collect information that is pertinent and necessary to manage your relationship with us. We will limit the collection and use of personal information to that which is required for valid business purposes, or to comply with legislation. We may ask for optional additional personal information to better target our marketing to suit your preferences.

## 3\. HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Where possible Home Hardware Stores Limited will collect your information directly from you, often directly through the management of your relationship with us.

## 4\. YOUR CONSENT IS NEEDED

Home Hardware Stores Limited will obtain your consent to collect, use or disclose your personal information. The method of obtaining this consent depends on the type of personal information being collected, used or disclosed. If there is a specific need to collect, use or disclose your personal information that is considered sensitive, we will obtain your express consent to collect, use or disclose that information. Your express consent may be provided in writing, verbally or electronically. Where you voluntarily give us personal information, we will consider your consent to be implied.

Should you decide to withdraw your consent allowing Home Hardware Stores Limited to collect, use, or disclose your personal information considered reasonable to fulfil the needs of our relationship, we may not be able to continue to provide you with the programs, services or benefits offered under our national programs.

## 5\. WE WILL LIMIT THE USE AND DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Home Hardware Stores Limited will use and disclose your personal information in accordance with our privacy policy, for the purposes it was collected, for managing your relationship with us, or as required by law.

We will provide you with the opportunity to opt out of programs and services. You may do that when you receive a communication from us, or by contacting our Privacy Officer.

We do not give or sell any personal information to third parties for marketing purposes unless you have given express consent for us to do so.

We may disclose your personal information within our company, to affiliated companies, and to other companies or organizations that provide services on our behalf, whether upon our direction or the direction of a third party. We will only provide those companies and organizations the information required to deliver the service and will prohibit them from using that information for any other purpose. These companies and organizations with which we share your personal information are bound by appropriate agreements with Home Hardware Stores Limited to secure and protect your personal information.

## 6\. WE WILL LIMIT THE LENGTH OF TIME WE RETAIN YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Home Hardware Stores Limited will establish a retention period for all personal information collected. We will only keep your personal information on our records so long as it is needed for its identified purposes, or as required by law.

## 7\. WE WILL KEEP YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION UP TO DATE AND ACCURATE

Home Hardware Stores Limited will keep your personal information as accurate, complete and up-to-date as necessary. By contacting our Privacy Officer, you may update and amend your personal information we have on file to ensure its accuracy and completeness. If there is a disagreement or a discrepancy with regard to an issue of accuracy, this will be noted on your file.

## 8\. WE WILL PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Home Hardware Stores Limited utilizes safeguards designed to protect the confidentiality and security of your personal information. Appropriate safeguards will also be used when we destroy your personal information.

Some or all of the personal information we collect may be stored or processed on servers located outside your jurisdiction of residence, including in the United States, whose data protection laws may differ from the jurisdiction in which you live. As a result, this information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in those jurisdictions according to laws in those jurisdictions.

## 9\. YOUR RIGHT TO ACCESS

Home Hardware Stores Limited supports your right to access personal information that we have collected about you. To make a request for access to your personal information we have on file, please contact our Privacy Officer.

Note that complete access cannot be guaranteed due to certain legal restrictions to your right to access. For example, you will not have access to files that contain information about other individuals or information that is confidential to Home Hardware Stores Limited. If you are denied access, Home Hardware Stores Limited will notify you of the reason and of any recourse available to you. Home Hardware Stores Limited will also endeavour to provide you with the factual information that pertains to you and is contained in those files.

## 10\. COMPLETE PRIVACY POLICY

This Privacy Statement is Home Hardware Stores Limited’s Privacy Commitment to you. If you have questions about our Privacy Commitment, please contact our Privacy Officer:

Privacy Officer  
Home Hardware Stores Limited  
34 Henry St. W  
St. Jacobs, Ontario  
N0B 2N0

Or by calling 519–664–4655

## **A NOTE ABOUT OUR DEALERS**

Home Hardware, Home Hardware Building Centres, Home Building Centres and Home Furniture stores are owned and operated by a member of your community. If you have a privacy concern relating to your relationship with one of our Stores or would like a copy of its individual Privacy Statement, please contact the Store directly. For a complete listing of our Stores and their phone numbers, please click here.

Updated June 17, 2018
